// List of global variables
var correctAnswer = 0;
var inccorectAnswers = 0;
var time = 10;
var questionNumber = 0;
var intervalId;

// Creating on click event that will start the game and display the first question

$("#start").on("click", function() {
  game();
});

function game() {
  // This will display questions on the screen
  $("#question").text(questions[questionNumber].question);
  $("#a").text(questions[questionNumber].a);
  $("#b").text(questions[questionNumber].b);
  $("#c").text(questions[questionNumber].c);
  $("#d").text(questions[questionNumber].d);

  // Setting countdown
  intervalId = setInterval(count, 1000);
}
$(".answers").on("click", function() {
    
   var userInput = $(this).attr("data-value");
    console.log(userInput);
  if (userInput === questions[questionNumber].correctAnswer) {
    correctAnswer++;
    reset();
  } else {
    inccorectAnswers++;
    // console.log(inccorectAnswers)
    reset();
    
  }
  // Score count
  //questionNumber++; // posibly be inside of reset function
  //     //$("#image-div").html("src", "assets/images/win.gif"); <-- need to add the timeer to keep it on the screen for 10sec
});

function count() {
  time--;
  $("#timer").text(time);
  if (time === 0) {
    reset();
  }
}

function reset() {
  clearInterval(intervalId);
  $("#question").text("");
  $("#a").text("");
  $("#b").text("");
  $("#c").text("");
  $("#d").text("");
  $("#image-div").html("");
  questionNumber++;
  time = 10;
  game();
}

// Questions
var questions = [
  {
    question: "One human hair can support how many kilograms?",
    a: "Three",
    b: "Five",
    c: "Seven",
    d: "Nine",
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question:
      "In ʻBen Hurʼ, which modern thing can be seen during the chario scene?",
    a: " A waitress",
    b: "A car",
    c: "A postbox",
    d: "A street lamp",
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    Question: "Whatʼs the best way to stop crying while peeling onions?",
    a: "Sniff almonds",
    b: "Suck lemons",
    c: "Eat cheese",
    d: "Chew gum",
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },

  {
    question: "What was Karl Marxʼs favorite color?",
    a: "Brown",
    b: "Blue",
    c: "Red",
    d: "Purple",
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },

  {
    question: "How old was the youngest Pope?",
    a: "11",
    b: "17",
    c: "22",
    d: "26",
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Which animal sleeps for only five minutes a day?",
    a: "A chameleon",
    b: "A koala",
    c: "A giraffe",
    d: "A beaver",
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },

  {
    question: "The bikini was originally called the what?",
    a: "Vest",
    b: "Range",
    c: "Line",
    d: "Atom",
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },

  {
    question: "Whatʼs a frogʼs favorite color?",
    a: "Blue",
    b: "Orange",
    c: "Yellow",
    d: "Brown",
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "On average, what do you do 15 times a day?",
    a: "Laugh",
    b: "Burp",
    c: "Break wind",
    d: "Lick your lips",
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "The inventor of the paint roller was of which nationality?",
    a: "Hungarian",
    b: "Canadian",
    c: "Norwegian",
    d: "Argentinian",
    correctAnswer: "b"
  }
];
